

# CONTACT

- (360) 249-7687
- Arlington, WA
- in bryce-alan-fleck

# **SKILLS**

- React.js
- Angular
- Node
- Laravel
- Vue.js
- AngularJS
- Express.js
- AWS Lambda
- AWS Amplify
- JavaScript
- Python
- Django

# **BRYCE ALAN FLECK**

# Full Stack Developer

I'm a dedicated and efficient full-stack developer experienced in React, Angular, Vue/Node, Laravel, Django.

As a full-stack developer, I can create complete End to End applications from the database to the UI. My strong stacks include React.js, Next.js for the front end, Node/Express and Laravel for the back end, AWS for the cloud platform, and MySQL, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB for the database.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2023 - Present

Self Employed

# SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER(JS/PHP/PYTHON)

2018 - 2023

#### Bright Pattern

- Front-end development of a React web application for an in-site corporate cafe, consisting of 2 SPAs. This web app used React and Redux as the core of the front-end structure while using MUI as a styling library and Laravel for the back end.
- Developed React JS frontend app using Mapbox, and Kepler.gl, Redux, Axios, Apex Charts, and Webpack
- Developing screens for a mobile-first web app that serves people applying for benefits.
- Requirements Analysis, Design, Development, Implementation, and Production using Node and React/ Next.js/ React Native.
- Have worked on big data (Splunk enterprise) to generate the Rest API and integrated that API to Clientside code using Node JS, and Express JS.
- Responsible for developing Mobile Applications for (IOS & Android) using React-Native.
- Built the API for the microservice and deployed it using AWS EC2 instances

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

2016 - 2018

#### Coalition Technologies

- Created proof-of-concept using responsive web design, Node.js, React JS, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Designed frontend architecture, gather requirements, develop features, test, and maintain custom internalfacing UIs to power Ruggable Operations using React (Hooks & Context API), Apollo Client, and GraphQL.
- Built the back end of the application using Node.js and Sequelize

- PHP
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- Firebase
- Jasmine
- Jest

## LANGUAGE

- English
- Spanish

- Developed APIs for operations software using Node, Express, Apollo Server, GraphQL, TypeORM, and PostgreSQL.
- Built the top component of the website, which includes a photo carousel using React and CSS
- Performed ETL process and loaded over 5mil rows of data into a MySQL database, and deployed it using AWS EC2 instances

#### SENIOR PHP DEVELOPER

2012 - 2016

Pivotal Software, Inc.

- Created and managed C.R.U.D API using Laravel and Slim Framework on an Nginx Server with PHP 7.2. This backend application would also communicate with a local MySQL database and AWS S3 Buckets to save required user data.
- Designed database schema and used effective and efficient methods to acquire necessary information from MySQL.
- Managed most of the projects from beginning to end.
   Gathered requirements, and architected, designed, and developed the solutions.
- Implemented dynamic, fast-loading, and responsive web application with PHP Restful web API to process and handle data between server and client.
- Responsible to build, testing, and deploy an interactive mobile and desktop web application using front-end technologies JavaScript, ReactJS, HTML5 & CSS3.
- Manipulating & presenting JSON data from RESTful API to Front End UI.
- Playing multiple roles in a startup environment.
- Developed multiple APIs for the hotels, condos, cruises, and cars search engine company web app.

# WEB DEVELOPER (HTML/CSS/JQUERY/PHP)

2010 - 2012

#### Siemens PLM Software

Work collaboratively with the company team to provide backend web development using PHP and Ajax for a top 100 US ecommerce reseller. The main responsibilities are site automatization through cron jobs, bug fixes, increasing functionality, adding new modules, connecting with third parties through REST API (eBay, Amazon MWS, Listrak, Mautic, Walmart, PayPal...) developing the company's CRM and rewriting Perl scripts to PHP.

- Converted the provided PSDs into web pages using HTML and CSS.
- Used of Bootstrap to make responsive websites.
- Used of PHP for server side scripting.
- Maintained and Bug fixation of existing websites.

# **EDUCATION**

# City University of Seattle

2005 - 2009

Bachelor of Computer Science

• Honors: cum laude (GPA: 3.8/4.0)